an area of the matter the channel i hope you guys are doing extremely
well today's video is going to be extremely important because i'm going to talk
about the current generation's obsession with solving five hundred or more lead core problems
wherever i see the like assault five hundred have sold eight hundred thousand barrels
what we are going to talk about in this video so i'm not sure
if you know me or not so during my time added
internet amazon after that i joined media dot net as a software engineer and
four guys who know me dot net
are the interviews that media dot net after that i went on to give
interviews of facebook and google and kulgam working at google
like this
entirely in and out so i know how much is required been seeing this
pattern lately that people are just running behind those numbers and that is what
i will be talking about in this video understand numbers give you a dopamine
but you need to use your brain wisely because time is critical like you
cannot just waste your time just to increase those
to decorate your profile because at the end of the day what matters is
your skill sets so what we will be talking about in this video as
the things that you need to do other things that you do not need
to do when you're using lead called for interview prep
do not solve problems that you know you can add is very very important
what seen is people know the solution of a problem this stereotype the code
just click on the submit because they want to see that accepted thing dude
what are you doing not upskilling yourself you're just satisfying your ego that yes
it's always actually didn't you already have solved that problem that is why you're
able to solve the problem in one go you only solve problems for which
you don't know the solution you only solved problem for which you did
don't know if this solution will work or not any problem that you know
that you have solved this problem or i know that the solution is definitely
going to have avoided move ahead that is what you need to do before
my amazon internship interview the number of problems i did was overall two fifty
only it could make sure those
problems so it's important that you solve quality problems that you cannot solve on
the first call that you've like you are not sure of the optimal solution
only those problems are the ones that you should solve and please do not
solve for the sake of the numbers the competition rising up solving problems alone
is not going to help you you will need to build projects
need to get mock interviews resume has to be polished enough and you'll be
requiring reference when the time is their total recommended
check out replaced because they have some amazing mentors why am i talking about
maintains because everyone yes everyone has a personalised query where struggling from something or
something else and they need a personalized roadmap and this is where the main
test comment they will be sitting with you they'll be hearing all your doubts
and after that we'll be preparing you a personalised roadmap
oh that roadmap and every week they'll be checking up on you okay did
you do it hey did you do it and when someone is watching trust
me you tend to perform a lot better once you're prepared once you have
done your projects after that they'll be helping you with mock interview so that
before the interview you get a vibe of how the interviews after that they
will be polishing your rescue
once you're done with that they'll also be helping you with reference because most
of the engineers have a good circle as well so what are you waiting
for book your free trial session with the mental of your choice right now
at replaced
thousand in order to get extra housing projects
to try learning topics packed and vice versa
people want to learn a topic that is great what they do is they
go well it could
any other platform
and the sorted by easy medium hard start solving all the easy ones then
the go-to medium then they go too hard they end up solving hundred hundred
fifty problems and most of them are repeating patterns not required is not necessary
what you need to do is to identify patterns for an example a topic
like binary search it has probably ten or twelve
what you need to do is ready to cover these ten or twelve patterns
for every pattern if need to problems
whatever number of problems you need to understand that pattern that it might happen
for a pattern in binary search for a pattern in my research you might
need one to understand it and depth the moment you understand that pattern that
move ahead just do not solve like keep solving problems just because you enjoy
that pattern it's important to finish up
wrap up the topics quickly like i made this binary search playlist what made
it and
do you understand it and you can solve any of the progress so please
do not solve problems by just giving topic names it is good when you
are revising but we're learning it's important to be quick because you need to
do a lot of other things as well point number three
participate in contest why am i saying a common trend whoever is solving five
hundred eight hundred thousand and fourteen hundred whatever is the number most of them
are not participating in contests and at the end of the day whenever they
go into the coding now struggling to understand one thing that in the difficulty
level is slightly tougher because the competition is
so you have to be at your best you cannot say that i'll get
the interview until clear written order to get that interview collect thousands of people
appearing for an opening so you have to be prepared for that coding out
and nowadays the coding nouns are getting tougher and tougher that is why participating
in contest is very critical water coding rooms it's a closed
payment with unknown questions with a timer how can you replicate that how can
you practice that environments the best ways to participate in contests just opening a
lead core problem and solving is not under that pressure women try not under
the pressure of that time timer ticking up you got you need to practice
that is why please please participate
in contest and after the contest is finished pleas of solve the problems that
even not able to because this is how you'll understand if you are able
to apply those concepts or not and whichever concepts are still weak try to
solve more and more problems on that instead of solving random problems and like
increasing your number count got a phone number four
to diversify topics as much as you can why am i saying that i've
seen a lot of profiles that sold like five hundred eight hundred lead to
problems and when i go over the profile i see that the topic specifically
the advanced topics like p
the trees try haven't solved a lot of problems on its side a notion
that people are solving a lot of problems but they're solving something like a
binary search list the upper like the easy medium section a lot but when
it comes to the harder like advanced concepts that kind of backing up so
it's critical that when you're picking up a topic don't get into this notion
that
i'm going to learn it entirely
binary research because you can never learn a topic entirely
you can never learn anything entirely on this planet you're picking up
assume your playlist it's fine it's time to move on you'll be tested when
you're giving contest the moment you give contest you'll find the problem on by
research if you cannot absolve and that is how you learn you just cannot
stick to binary search for six months we gotta move to advance topics to
try to diversify topics as much as you can try touching
all the topics because that is important having a well diversified number on all
the topics is like that is what will matter when you go to interviews
only you can be on any topic and for that it should be knowing
that topic in order to at least give it a try that is why
try diversifying topics do not look at numbers just keep solving at the end
of one year you will see that the numbers are good look at your
profile they will be great solving it for the purpose of the numbers it
won't help your
quality problems pattern by and on all the topics you should definitely check out
seven years ago
the link in the description you get video solutions as well you get the
articles as well you get the c plus plus job of javascript code as
well and that is all you will be requiring for your interview prep along
with getting your project's done as important as well so do not miss out
on that aspect and a possible to get a mentor who will be leaving
your resume will be taking your mock interviews
pushing you every now and then checkout replaced for some amazing mentors the link
between the reception
video and and some other videos
oh