so at this point we're pretty familiar with all of the data type that
come native to see we have characters and floats and integers and doubles and
we're also familiar now with the cs fifty data types of strings and bulls
but that doesn't limit everything that we can do we surely can do more
indeed with structures that cause this inability to start to
our own data types might be useful for our own programs what's cool about
structures as they allow us to unify many different variables of different data types
into a single brand new type and we can give that new type it's
own unique type name as a way to identify it this isn't the first
time we've seen the ability to combine multiple variables together
either we've seen that with a raise remember the restriction with a raise that
we can only combine things of the same type we can have a whole
bunch of integers are whole bunch of floats but we can't mix them up
with structures we actually can we can group together logical we can live together
elements that have a logical connection to one another so for example we can
group together a structure for like say a student where
a student would have an id number which is probably an integer but they
also have a name which is a string and they might have a g
p a which is a float and we can have all of these things
tied together and basically what's a super variable is a variable that has other
variables within it the way to do to do this and see is actually
pretty straightforward simpson text might look like this instead of a student
in this example let's use a car we introduced the concept of a structure
by saying struct we're about to define a structure type and in particular we're
going to define a struct car and struct car actually now becomes our type
name it's not just car it's struct car inside of the curly braces from
this point forward
we can define all of the different variables that we want inside of our
super variable so for example here are some things that are common to cars
they have a year either they were manufactured we have a model and a
license plate and an odometer which has a number of miles and maybe they
have an engine size which in the united states is usually represented as a
float for
how many leaders on the engine the capacity is and notice that these are
all different datatypes mixed together we have integers and we have two strings and
we have a float or double all mixed up inside of one super variable
to finish our definition of the structure we have a closing curly brace and
then really important that common syntax error is a semi colon at the end
which
she completes our definition of a struct car once we defined the structure and
usually we defined our structure at the very top of our program up near
our lb includes in our lb defines we also might define them in a
separate dot h file because maybe we're using this type definition in several different
files or several different programs and so it may
sense to define it somewhere outside of one outside of a single file and
have it be a dot h file that we can pound include in multiple
different contexts now we have effectively created this new type and we can start
to use it and and we can create variables of this type just like
we can create variables of any other type int x that's how we create
an integer called x struck
the car why that's how we create a variable called y of type struct
car so that's how we create the variable overall how do we create the
individual fields or members of that or rather how do we access the individual
fields are members of that structure we can do so using something called the
dot operator let's take a look at what that looks like so the top
here i have a variable declaration struct car my car again here the type
is struct car and the variable name is my car from this point forward
whenever i want to refer to a field or a member within my car
which is again the variable name i can use the dot operator to access
those individuals
fields within my car so i could say for example my car dot year
equals two thousand and eleven i can't just a year equals two thousand and
eleven year is something that is part of my car so i have to
always refer to it in the context of my car i can i can
say stir copy my car dot plate cs fifty remember it's a string i
can't just ask
sign it i have to copy that string into the variable i can say
my car dot odometer equals five o five o five or anything else that
i want to do i can set the i can set the engine size
and i can set the model i can do whatever else i want to
do
just by accessing the fields similar to this
but structures like variables of all other data we don't have to just use
the stack for this we don't just have to say struct car my car
semicolon we could dynamically allocate this if we don't know at the beginning of
our program for example that we're going to need a certain number of these
things we can just declare this on the fly dynamically using pointers of course
in order to access our fields in that situation we don't use just the
dot operator because we have a pointer to a structure we also have to
first as you may recall dereference that pointer and then access it's fields it
adds a little bit of extra stuff but let's take a look again here
so here now instead of statically declaring a struct car called my car i'm
going to dine
chemically allocate a struct car called my car so struct car star my car
and then i'm going to malloc space for a struct car and here's the
cool thing about size of size of is not just built in it doesn't
just happen to know just the size of integers characters floats and doubles it
can also figure out on the fly exactly how much space is required
fired for a struct car so you don't have to go through and figure
out like okay well this is probably like thirty bytes or something you can
just say size of struct car and let the computer figure it out for
you so struct carstar my car he calls malloc size of struct car that
dynamically allocated on the heap one chunk of memory large enough to hold a
single struct car within it
and then i can access my fields by first d referencing the pointer and
then once i've dereference the pointer i can then use the dot operator to
access the fields again it's very similar to what we just saw but the
syntax here is a little cumbersome right now we have extra parentheses we have
this star we have this dot surely there's gotta be an easier way see
pro
grammar is love then it'd be easier ways to do things in fact there
is a shortcut for this it so happens that accessing the field of a
structure via it's pointer is a common enough operation that there is an entirely
different operator that allows us to do this much more simply and is called
the arrow operator which is a hyphen and then a
a greater than symbol literally making it look like it's an arrow and it
does two operations back to back so for the first thing it does is
it d references the pointer which is on the left of the arrow and
then it's going to access the field which is on the right of the
arrow so for example
this is what the code looked liked before this is what we just haven't
said a second ago where i'm due referencing pointers and then act using the
dot operator to access the fields here's what the same code would look like
with the arrow syntax and the same thing is happening here the first thing
i'm doing is i'm d referencing my car but the arrow operator does that
for me i don't have to use the star syntax it just knows
as if i have an arrow there i needed the first d reference the
thing on the left and then i can access the field on the right
so using the arrow operator is a great way to have a shorthand for
access in the field of a structure to which you only have a pointer
and you'll probably use this a fair amount so it's syntax definitely to to
befriend and to get used to
i'm doug lloyd this is the us fifty